# Miracle Agholor

Delta State, Nigeria



miracleagholor1@gmail.com



+2349051927808



linkedin.com/in/miracle-agholor-b16b88150

## Summary

An engineering health and safety representative supervisor, IT Professional, Project Manager and Business analyst with accumulated years of experience in the various industry. I am a tech savvy person who works and multitasks tirelessly in other to proffer solutions to arising needs.

## **Experience**



#### Web Developer

Freelance

Sep 2022 - Present (8 months)

Creating Web application and rending web application solutions

### Health Safety Environment Representative

IDSL/NNPC & BGP/CNPC JOINT VENTURES

Oct 2019 - Dec 2022 (3 years 3 months)

- Exercise emergency authority to prevent or stop unsafe acts when immediate action is required.
- Maintains awareness of active and developing situations.
- Ensures there are safety messages in each Incident Action Plan.
- Participate in planning meetings to identify any health and safety concerns inherent in the operations daily work-plan.
- Review the Incident Action Plan for safety implications.
- Investigate accidents that have occurred within incident areas.
- Ensure preparation and implementation of Site Safety and Health Plan (SSHP).
- Inspects the site to ensure it is a hazard-free environment.
- · Conducts toolbox meetings



#### 🦍 Information Technology Technician

Federal Ministry of Power, Works and Housing

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 4 months)

- · Repairing or replacing damaged hardware.
- Upgrading the entire system to enable compatible software on all computers.
- Installing and upgrading anti-virus software to ensure security at the user level.
- Establishing good relationships with all departments and colleagues.
- Conducting daily backup operations.
- Managing technical documentation.
- Installing and configuring hardware and software components to ensure usability.
- Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
- Ensuring electrical safety standards are met.
- Performing tests and evaluations of new software and hardware.

• Providing support to users and being the first point of contact for error reporting.

## Apprentice Technician

Olori Auto-electrical engineering Workshop

Mar 2018 - Aug 2018 (6 months)

- . Learn the process and techniques involved in diagnosis of ECU system alerts and check engine faults detection.
- . Replacement, Repairs and maintenance of all electrical faults in an automobile including auto-sensors.

## Leader and President, Community Development Service Group for Information Communications Technology

National Youth Service Corps

Sep 2017 - Apr 2018 (8 months)

- · Coordinate the activities of the group
- Organizing weekly general meetings and key comrades' executive meetings.
- Give report to Schedule officer and Local government inspector.
- Liaise with the State ICT Coordinator on the advance of ICT projects
- Prepare sensitization meetings and hold meetings with schools, communities.
- Liaise with Tech companies to train and build techies amongst Corp members.
- Plan and prepare for yearly ICT community Project.
- Meet with NGOs and Governmental Agencies to aid the sponsorship of Group project.

## Junior hardware technician

Cinex Computer

Jan 2015 - Nov 2015 (11 months)

- Builds/configured custom built units to customer specifications, performs upgrades of hardware and operating systems.
- Performed on-site commercial and residential computer diagnosis and repair, software and hardware installation, and network installation and optimization.
- Administered all desktop related functions including hardware installation, software set-up, networking setup, and system configuration.
- Repaired/Upgraded Microsoft operating systems, including complete re-installations to finding drivers for all hardware on the systems.

## Computer Hardware Maintenance Apprentice

**Chinex Computers** 

Jul 2013 - Oct 2013 (4 months)

- . Learn Computer Hardware diagnosis
- . Troubleshooting Techniques
- . Hardware repairs
- . Software installations antivirus updates
- . Operating system installations and update

#### **Education**



Delta State Polytechnic Otefe-Oghara, Delta State, Nigeria

Higher National Diploma (HND), Computer Engineering 2012 - 2016

## Delta State Polytechnic Otefe-Oghara, Delta State, Nigeria

National Diploma, Computer Engineering Nov 2012 - Oct 2014

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Award in HSE 123, British International Safety Organization UKHSE Limited 00187301
- **Environmental Impact Assessment** Department of Petroleum Resources (DPR)
- Novelle Basic First AID/CPR Novelle Center
- Certificate of Accomplishment In CISCO-ACNA Aptech 1155
- PROJECT MANAGEMENT British project management Academy (BPMA)
  141720
- ASNT NDT Level II Certification Ultrasonic Testing (ASNT-NDT2-UT) Tonmerit International Limited
- General HSE Institute of Safety professionals of Nigeria

#### **Skills**

HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • React.js • SASS • Front-End Development • HSEQ • Firefighting • Risk Management • Project Management

#### **Honors & Awards**

Certificate of National Service - National Youth Service Corp
Apr 2018

A one year compulsory National Service to my Country